So you have completed your Fusion model
and you want to export some of the faces out as SVGs.
There is not an inbuilt way in Fusion to do this easily,
but thankfully, we're able to download various plug-ins
from the Autodesk App Store, which enable us to do various things.
One such thing is exporting faces as SVG files.
To do this, we're going to have to go up to Google Chrome.
And when we're on Chrome, we're going to type in Autodesk App Store.
And clicking on the first link will take
us to the App Store, where we can then search through an app.
The app we're looking for is called Shaper Utilities.
As you type it, it should auto-fill it out.
Then you can click on it and it will take you to the page.
Clicking on the plugin will then take you
to its homepage, where you can then go ahead and download the plugin yourself.
It's important to make sure you choose the correct operating system,
whether you're on a Mac or whether you're on a PC.
Once you've switched over to the correct
one, I'm on a Windows device, so I chose Windows, you'll press Download.
If you aren't already logged in, it will ask you to log in and you'll have
to press the Download button again, I'm already logged into my Fusion account.
I'll then click Download, and it will begin downloading
the installation file down here in the corner.
Once that's finished, we will open that file up,
install it, and then it should be available in Fusion after a quick restart.
Now that this is finished downloading,
we can click on it and it should begin the installation process.
If you get this Windows protecting your
PC, you can always press the More Info and press Run anyway.
Awesome.
Now we're going to need to restart our
Fusion in our application so that our plugin will appear.
I'm going to quickly close that down.
Now let's reopen up our design.
The picnic table,
which is what we made in the last tutorial.
Now looking at our fusion model, there are going to be three things
that we're going to want to export as SVG files.
We're going to want to do this base of our table-top.
We're also then going to do our U-leg over
here, and then our third single leg by itself.
In order to get to the plugin that we installed, we need to go up here
to utilities and you'll find over on the side here,
there will be a new section with a little shape called Export to Origin.
This is the plugin that we just installed.
You can see by the same logo.
We will click on this and then we're going to make a selection.
Now it says here, Select a single face to define the top of the model.
All details that can be cut from the top
will be exported as an appropriately coloured, coded, SVG file.
If you select Advanced, you can choose a body or choose just a face or an entire
sketch if you wanted to export the sketch instead.
However, most of the time you won't need to use the advanced.
Instead, we'll just need to define the top or the top face of your model.
Let's start with our picnic table.
I'm going to select that.
It will show here one selected and it will
be highlighted in blue, and then we'll press OK.
Next, it will ask you to save that SPG file to an appropriate location.
For now, I'm just going to save this to my downloads folder.
We will call this, picnic table top.
And Save.
And we repeat that process for each of the other faces that we need to export.
So again, click on the shape or origin,
choose the face, make sure it says selected, and press OK.
And then give it a name, U-Leg.
Click New Table U-Leg.
Save.
One more time, export origin, choose the face, select OK, and give it a name.
Picnic Table, Straight, Leg.
Now we've saved those three files to the SVG files.
Let's say that we wanted to laser cut out these three pieces.
In order to do that,
we would need to get the files set up in illustrator so we can have
the appropriate colors attached to each of the lines and the fill shapes.
For now, let's just close Fusion and
we will open up the illustrator and show you what the files look like as
they were exported from the Shaper Utilities and how we can correct
that in illustrator to be appropriate for your laser cover.
All right, with illustrator open,
I'm actually going to open up a template, which I've created to help me remind
myself of the different colors and the line thicknesses that I need.
This template will be available in the description because it's very
helpful to have all the information that you need available.
So when we are getting a file ready for the laser cutter,
we need to make sure each of the lines are set to the appropriate color,
and we need to make sure the line width is set to 0.001.
Raster means that it's going to be based on the shade of black that it's going
to be, will determine how much power the laser is going to have.
So it enables you to laser cut or etch into your wood an actual image because it
will do some darker parts darker and some lighter parts lighter.
If there's something that you need to have
that done, it needs to be in black and white.
If there's a line that we're going to be
the laser will be cutting around, we need to make sure that it's got full red.
So that means that in an RGB file, the red is going to be at 255,
and then the blue and the green are both going to be at zero and zero.
If we're etching,
meaning we're not cutting all the way through the piece of wood or the material
that we're using, then we're going to want to make sure it's completely blue.
That means that the red, the green and the blue,
the red and the green are going to be zero and the blue is going to be at 255.
Let's get one of our files that we just
exported into here and we'll just drag this picnic table top into illustrator.
Once in illustrator, we're going to want to change the lines
because currently we have a black fill with no outline.
The first thing we need to do is actually change our colour mode from CMYK to RGB.
Because remember
that in order for the laser cutter to interpret the colors correctly,
there needs to be an RGB mode and there needs to be a red if we're going to be
doing cutting, which is what we're going to be doing.
In our file to change the document type
to RGB, we're going to go to File, down to Document Colour mode.
I'm going to choose RGB colour.
Sometimes this may not always work and you
may actually have your colour palette not showing any colours.
But if you go into it and just sure you
select RGB again, it should make sure that it auto-corrects
so that you're able to get lots of different colors.
Once you've got your RGB mode set,
change from CMYK to RGB, we're then going to want to go up to here
to our stroke and change our stroke to the values that we talked about before.
So our red is going to be want to be 255,
with our green and our blue both being at zero.
Next, we want to change our stroke width.
Our stroke width and line width needs
to be at 0.001. So over here on the stroke,
we will just click in this box and change this to 0.001 and hit Enter.
Lastly, we need to remove the fill because
any black that is on our file, it will raster it.
It will do a back and forth like printing
from an inkjet printer and will be completely burnt out across the top.
We're going to click on the black and we're going to remove the fill.
So now it's gone completely.
And if I select out of here,
you should be able to see a faint red line where it's going to cut.
Secondly, I can see that there are two
other lines here which are currently black.
I don't want those to be rastered.
I want them to be cut out because they are handles.
I'm going to select that object, go to my Fill, remove the Fill,
change my stroke to red 255, green 0 and blue 0.
Then change my stroke width to 0.001, hit Enter.
I'm going to do this for each object that I want to cut out.
No fill, red all the way up to 255, stroke width 0.001, Enter.
This is what your file should look like
when you want to send it up to the laser cutter.
I'm going to do this for each individual piece that we have.
Once you've done this process to all parts
of the depicting table, you're going to want to copy and paste
each of the individual parts into the template provided.
There are a couple of reasons we want to do this.
One of the reasons is that the template is set to the size of the laser cutter.
The template I've got open here is set
to a bigger laser cutter, which is 810 by 450 millimetres.
And if you look in the description,
there is a template for the smaller one, which is 600 by 450.
The other reason that we want to put our individual pieces into this template is
because this template is set to millimetres.
If we looked in our picnic table top SVG file and tried to look at the size
of an object, we would see that it is set to point values.
And we actually want this to be set
to millimeter values before we send it to the laser cutter.
So on our template folder, it's actually already set up to be in millimeters.
So to copy something from one file to another, we're going to select
everything in the file by pressing File, pressing CTRL A or Command A if you're
on a Mac, then pressing CTRL C or Command C to copy.
Then moving over to our template file and pressing CTRL V or Command V to paste.
And this will paste in our file that we had taken from the other one.
Now I can see that my tabletop is currently rotated the wrong direction.
In order to rotate this around, I'm going to take my mouse over to one
of the corners until it goes into a little 90 degree angle with two arrows on it.
I can click and drag to then rotate this piece around 90 degrees.
When you're rotating,
if you hold down the Shift key, you'll be able to snap it in 45 degree increments.
Then just move it down to the white portion of the template and you can see
how much space your table is going to take up on the laser cutter.
Now that I have my picnic table top within
the template, I can see that I'm probably only going to want to have this as its own
laser cut file because it takes up so much of the space of the laser cutter.
I will probably do the U-leg and the straight leg on a separate file.
Before I save this file, I want to make sure that it's going to be
the right size to fit the piece of material that I'm going to have,
or make sure I cut the material that goes into the laser cutter to the right size.
To do this while selecting the biggest
object within your space, you can go up here to the transform tool and select it.
Over here under width and height, it will tell you in millimeters the width
of the object and the height of the object.
The reason it shows you the width and height in millimeters within this
template is because it's set that the unit of measurement is set as millimeters.
If you tried to do this within the other
individual files that Fusion made for us, you would see that it is set as point,
which is good when you're working on objects.
But before you send the object to a laser
cutter or another device that's going to be using millimeters as the unit
of measurement, it's always a good idea to check it to make sure
that the millimeter size is the correct size that you need.
So this file is ready for me to save and send to the laser cutter.
And that's it. That's how we export
some faces from our Fusion model using the Shaper Utility to then get them
into Illustrator, set up the colours correctly,
place them into a template and save them ready to send to the laser cutter.